<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Lance&#39;s Quips &amp; Quibbles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Lance&#39;s Quips &amp; Quibbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Initial migration complete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/initial-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/initial-migration/</guid>
      <description>The site has been been updated to a new look. It has more content and a more professional pipeline.&#xA;I have to admit that I was a little worried when starting the migration process, even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with (or near) the new toolset for some time.&#xA;Part of my nervousness stems from earlier experiences, which have included some rather&amp;hellip;dramatic results.&#xA;No matter how well you plan, something always seems to go sideways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restart the engines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/restart-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/restart-engines/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to the ongoing work-in-progress. I&amp;rsquo;m blowing off the dust, sweeping away the cobwebs, and setting up new things.&#xA;This site serves as a practical portfolio and personal knowledgebase. It provides writing samples and illustrates my approach to technical writing. It also shares knowledge and lessons learned during my technical adventures.&#xA;I hope the content is engaging, practical, and has at least a bit of value. (I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to chase down the various typos, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to forgive a few rough edges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First post: Don&#39;t panic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/scribbles/journal/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Choose your greeting:&#xA;Hail and well met! Greetings, lifeform. Goooood Eeeeevvvening. Hello troubleshooter. Buh-doop beep? BLAAAT! Oh. It&amp;rsquo;s you. It&amp;rsquo;s been a looong time. How&amp;rsquo;ve you been? After many promises, multiple unfinished prototypes, and much pondering, it&amp;rsquo;s finally online. The site, I mean.&#xA;Here, you&amp;rsquo;ll find technical articles and posts related to things I&amp;rsquo;m working on, lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, solutions I&amp;rsquo;ve found, and other thoughts I thought worth sharing.&#xA;Feel free to browse, but I do ask that shenanigans be kept to a minimum…unless, of course, I&amp;rsquo;m allowed to be rambunctious as well.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
