<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Lance&#39;s Quips &amp; Quibbles</title>
    <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Lance&#39;s Quips &amp; Quibbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summer cleaning update</title>
      <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/summer-cleaning-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/summer-cleaning-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally planned this post as part of a &amp;ldquo;spring cleaning&amp;rdquo; project started with the best of intentions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I grabbed my keyboard, fired up the editor, and started putting ideas into markup. And then I needed to verify a few things. Ran into a few false start roadblocks. Started chasing side thoughts. Tried following up new questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So many grand ideas and plans. Heh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things took longer than I thought they would. Some internals were more complicated than I imagined. And, of course, I had other things demanding my attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six week progress report</title>
      <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/six-week-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/six-week-progress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been several weeks since I began reimplementing the website.  It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting experience to say the least.  It&amp;rsquo;s fun to create something new and watch it come together.  It&amp;rsquo;s also a little aggravating to find things that slipped through and need to be cleaned up.  It&amp;rsquo;s also educational to overcome bits of friction to create a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time to take stock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s gone well?  Well, here&amp;rsquo;s a high-level look at the recent changes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial migration complete</title>
      <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/initial-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/initial-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The site has been been updated to a new look.  It has more content and a more professional pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I was a little worried when starting the migration process, even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with (or near) the new toolset for some time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part of my nervousness stems from earlier experiences, which have included some rather&amp;hellip;dramatic results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how well you plan, something always seems to go sideways. And, truth be told, there were a couple of glitches along the way. (Fortunately, I noticed and resolved things quickly.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restart the engines</title>
      <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/restart-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/restart-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the ongoing work-in-progress.  I&amp;rsquo;m blowing off the dust, sweeping away the cobwebs, and setting up new things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site serves as a practical portfolio and personal knowledgebase.  It provides writing samples and illustrates my approach to technical writing.  It also shares knowledge and lessons learned during my technical adventures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope the content is engaging, practical, and has at least a bit of value.  (I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to chase down the various typos, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to forgive a few rough edges.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First post: Don&#39;t panic</title>
      <link>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lanceleonard.com/scribbles/journal/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choose your greeting:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
